다이간다는 방을 밝게 하고 적당히 떨어져서 봐!
Watch Daigunder in a bright room and keep some distance!
Смотри Дайгандера со включённым светом, сидя подальше от экрана!
다이간다!
Daigunder!
Дайгандер!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе,
마음의 눈을 열어라
Open your eyes of soul
Распахни шире око души
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
(Bakutou Sengen Daigunder)
Боевой претендент Дайгандер!
뜨거운 마음을 담아
With all your hot heart
Пусть меня охватит твой жар сердца,
오늘도 기적을 맹새해
I will make a miracle today too
Чтобы сотворить сумел я чудо
드래곤 소드 작렬이야
Dragon Sword bursts
Вспыхнет ярким светом Меч Дракона!
싸워야 할 라이벌은
The rival I have to fight against is
Побороть я должен свой упавший дух,
좌절하려는 내 자신
right here, dispirited myself
что пути к успеху преграждает мне,
어제보다도 진화해서
Evolve even more than yesterday
Вырасти сегодня больше, чем вчера
강해져라!
And become strong!
И сильнее стать!
다다다다 다 다 다 다다
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
드래곤 캐논!
Dragon Cannon!
Пушка Дракона!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе
에너지 전개로
Open up all your energy and
Дай энергии выход, сказав...
다다다다다다 다
Dadadadadada da
Дададададада-да!!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
쓰러트려라 타도해라
Defeat and knock down
Победи и врагов одолей
빛나는 강철의
Fighter of shining steel
Сталью сверкает тело твоё,
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
제 24 화
The 24th Episode
Эпизод 24
이탈선언!
Breakaway Declaration!
다시 만날 날까지!!
Until We Meet Again!!
(en: The Stand in the Sand)
더워...
So hot...
힘들어...
Tired...
덤으로 이 모래, 최악이야.
And this sand in addition... the worst.
이것도 저것도 다 네 탓이다!
It's all your fault!
누구 탓도 아니라고? 너 지옥에 간다, 지옥에!
It's nobody's fault? You're going to hell! To hell, you know!
뭐? 여기가 지옥이라고?
What? This place is the hell?
뭐, 그런 것일지도 모르지만.
Well, that might be right.
아니, 니가 그런 말 하지 마라!
Hey, you're not the one to say that!
젠장, 네가 그 이상한 걸 발견하지만 않았으면 이렇게는 안 됐어!
Dammit! If you didn't find out that strange thing, this wouldn't have happened!
왜 그래, 트라이혼?
What's up, Trihorn?
음? 이건?
Huh? What's this?
분명히 수상하네. 좋아, 내가 알아볼게.
This really is suspicious. I'll find out what it is.
파이터 체인지!
Fighter Change!
트라이혼! 넌 건너편에서 기다려라!
Trihorn! You can wait at the other side!
뭐야, 이건?!
What's this?!
뭐? 하늘을 날아서 감동이라고?
What? You're happy because you're flying?
그런 소리 할 때냐!
Is it time for that?!
트라이혼, 괜찮냐?
Trihorn, are you okay?
정말, 넉살 좋은 놈이라니까. 그럼 이런 곳과는 어서 작별을. 어?
You're one shameless guy. Anyway, let's bid farewell to a place like this... huh?
지금 충격으로 날개가 당했구나.
The shock just now has damaged my wings...
걸을 수밖에 없나.
We have to walk.
이 사막...
This desert...
정말, 언제까지 이어지는 거야, 이 사막은!
Really, where does this desert end at?!
뭐? 배고프다고?
What? You're hungry?
뭐뭐? 냉각수가 부족하다고?
What? Your coolant is running low?
그러니까 네가 할 소리 아니다!
Again, you're not in position to say that!
어? 데스펙터하고 트라이혼이 없어?
What? Despector and Trihorn aren't here?
그래. 어디에도 안 보이는구나.
Yes. I can't find them anywhere.
정말, 지금부터 트레이닝 할 건데.
Really... We were going to start training soon!
본렉스도 몰라?
Bonerex, do you know where they are?
걱정은 필요 없다. 놈들은 이제 어엿한 자립한 배틀 로봇. 이것도 나름의 이유가 있겠지.
No need to worry. They are honorable and independent battle robots. They should have a reason for this.
어쨌든 다 같이 찾아 보자.
Anyway, let's go find them all together.
그래!
Yeah!
모래가 관절 부분에 들어가 지금거리고...
Sands are getting into my joints and it's gritty...
덤으로 냉각수가 말라서 과열의 기미가 보이네.
Moreover, I think I'm going to overheat, thanks to my coolant evaporating.
뭐? 물 냄새가 난다고?
What? You smell water?
어, 어이! 같이 가!
H- hey! Wait for me!
포, 폭포다!
A- a waterfall!
여기엔 분수!
And a waterfall here!
풀이다!
A pool!
뭔 짓이야!
What was that for?!
그건 우리가 할 말이다.
That's our line.
너는!
Who are you?!
모르냐? 세계에서 손에 꼽는 부자, 하워드 재벌의 장남, 하워드 주니어.
Don't you know? I am one of the richest people in the world. I am Howard Junior, the eldest son of Howard Conglomerate.
그리고 세계 제일의 찬란한 로봇!
And the most gorgeous robots in the world!
샌드 데빌 브라더즈를!
They are Sand Devil Brothers!
네놈들 배틀 로봇이였냐!
So you guys were battle robots, too!
너희들이 내 부하가 된다면 원하는 만큼 물을 주지.
If you guys become my subordinates, you can have water as much as you want.
누가 네 자비 따위 받을 것 같냐!
We don't need your mercy!
그럼 사막에서 미라 로봇이라도 되라.
Then you'd better become mummy robots in desert.
하워드 씨?
Mr. Howard?
야, 하워드!
Hey, Howard!
또 이렇게 물을 낭비하고, 그 때문에 우리 우물이 말라서 작물에 물을 줄 수 없게 됐어!
You're wasting water again? Because of that, our well has dried up again and we can't water the plants!
트집은 잘 잡는구나. 우물이 마른 건 그 곳이 누더기라서지.
You're good at accusing. Your well dried up because your place is a scrap.
그런 소리 하다간 당신의 곳도 물이 마를 거야!
Your place is also going to dry up if you're like that!
그래!
Yeah!
공교롭게도 최고급 펌프를 쓰고 있으니 말야.
Too bad. I'm using highest grade pumps.
걱정할 필요 없다.
No need to worry.
이 무식쟁이!
You idiot!
이게! 샌드 데빌! 죽여라!
How dare you! Sand Devils! Kill them!
때려쳐라! 얘한테 뭔 짓이냐!
Forget it! What kind of thing are you doing to a child?!
해 볼텨?
Wanna fight?
흥, 재밌군. 지옥을 보여주지!
Hmph, interesting! I'll show you a hell!
가라, 샌드 데빌!
Go, Sand Devils!
싸우면 안 돼!
Don't fight!
칫. 김 빠지게.
Tch. How dissatisfying.
오늘은 관대하게 봐 주겠다. 어서 꺼져!
I'll let this pass for today. Get lost!
흥!
Hmph!
고마워! 난 사라!
Thank you! I'm Sarah!
린이야! 이 아기는 로라!
I'm Rin, and this kid is Laura!
어, 나는 데스펙터! 얜 트라이혼.
Err, I'm Despector, and this is Trihorn.
임마, 트라이혼! 꼴불견이다! 아무리 배가 고파도 말이지! 이럴 땐...
Hey, Trihorn! How unsightly of you! Even if you're hungry, you must-
저기, 괜찮으면 우리 집에서 쉬다 가.
Hey, if you'd like to, you can take a rest in my home.
되살아났다.
I'm revived.
꽤나 배가 고팠나 봐?
You guys must've been hungry!
역시 우리 통신기 고장났나 봐.
It looks like our communicator is broken.
그럼 다이랜드에는 통신할 수 없군.
Then we can't leave message to Dailand.
내 수리 부품도 없고, 어쩌냐.
I don't have my spare parts, too. What should we do now...
이 농장을 둘이서만 관리하고 있냬.
He's asking if you two are running this whole farm.
아니, 보통은 아빠하고 엄마하고 농작용 로봇이.
No. Usually, our parents and farming robots do that.
그래도 고장나서 마을에 수리하러 가셨어.
But since the robots were broken, they went to the village for repairs.
그 동안 우리가 집 지키고 있는 거야!
We're housewatching meanwhile!
대단하지!
Aren't we great?
그래도 아까 말한 대로, 우리 우물이 말라서 해야 하는 밭일도 잔뜩 있고...
But as I said before, our well has dried up and we have a lot to do...
언니! 다들 있으니까 괜찮을거야!
Sis! Since they're here, it's gonna be fine!
뭐라뭐라? 그런 거라면 우리가 수원을 찾아?
What, what? We're going to find a water source?
아, 그래, 그래, 아니, 야! 나도냐!
Oh, yeah, sure- no, hey! Me too?!
이야! 고마워!
Yay! Thanks!
뭐? 멍청한 소리 마!
What?! Don't be stupid!
뭐라고 해?
What's he saying?
알려 줘!
Tell us!
트라이혼이 수원을 찾을 동안 나보고 밭일을 도우란다!
He's telling me to help with the farming while he finds a water source!
정말?!
Really?!
흥! 내가 그럴 일을 할 리가...
Hmph! No way I'm going to do...
고마워, 데스펙터!
Thank you, Despector!
고마워! 덕분에 살겠어!
Thank you! You'll help us a lot!
쉬운 일이다, 아가씨.
It's an easy job, young lady.
그럼 거기에 하나 더 부탁해도 돼?
Then, can we ask you one more favor?
왜 내가 이런 일을...
Why am I doing this?
저런! 착하지, 착하지!
Good baby, good baby!
아빠가 파고 있던 곳인데...
My dad was digging here, but...
물이 전혀 안 나와서 포기했어.
he gave up because no water was to be found.
대단해!
Awesome!
힘내, 트라이혼!
Keep it up, Trihorn!
왜 그러냐!
What's wrong?
뭐라고?
What?
대부분은 암반이군. 여긴 시간이 걸리니까 다른 곳을 찾는 게 낫겠어.
It's mostly bedrock. It's better to find an another place since it will take time to dig this up.
라고 말하고 싶지만...
That's what I want...
안됐지만 슬슬 우리는 가야겠어.
Excuse us, but we have to go soon.
뭐?! 안 간다고?!
What?! You aren't going with me?!
모두한테 연락하지 않으면 걱정할 거야!
If we don't let them know, they'll worry about us!
정말 가야만 해?
Do you really have to go now?
가면 안돼!
Please don't go!
아, 아니, 그게, 저게...
Um, er, that's, well...
착하지, 착하지. 착하지, 착하지.
Good baby, good baby. Good baby, good baby.
에잇! 해가 질 때까지는 수원을 찾자!
Screw this! We're going to find a water source before the Sun falls!
고마워!
Thank you!
둘 다 최고야!
You two are the best!
폭투선언 다이간다
Bakutou Sengen Daigunder
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
by Subdivers
Russian TL by SutoKuroi
Subdivers 번역
폭투선언 다이간다
Bakutou Sengen Daigunder
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
by Subdivers
Russian TL by SutoKuroi
Subdivers 번역
정말 여기에 물의 기미가 느껴진다는 거지?
You sure that you feel water from here?
어? 뭐야, 이거?
Huh? What's this?
이게!
Damn!
어쨌든 쉬자.
Anyway, you should take a rest.
뭐, 그래.
Well, you're right.
열반응으로 봐서 둘이 여기 있었다는 건 틀림없어.
According to heat reaction, I'm sure that they were here.
그래도 이런 곳에서 뭘...
But what would they have done here?
그러게... 나도 이 주변은 별로 온 적이 없으니 말야.
I dunno... I usually don't come to this place, too.
이 냄새!
That smell!
왜 그래, 브라이온?
What's wrong, Bullion?
맛있는 냄새!
A tasty smell!
저기야!
That way!
어이, 잠깐, 모두!
Hey, wait for us!
이건...
What's that?
이렇게 한가롭게 있는 것도 오랜만이야!
It's been a while since the last time I've been so free!
있잖아, 트라이혼!
Hey, Trihorn!
앞으로도 계속 같이 있어줄 거야?
Are you going to be with us from now on?
아, 방금 응이라고 했지?
I know you just said yes!
트라이혼 최고야!
Trihorn, you're the best!
그럼 슬슬 시작해 볼까.
Then, let us begin.
응!
Yeah!
이 안에서 에너지 팩 냄새가 나.
I smell energy packs from there.
알아 볼게.
I'll find out what that is.
-흥, 일단 부딪혀보면 되지!
-그래!
-Then we'll find out by ourselves!
-Yeah!
잠깐! 안에 들어가지 마라!
Stop! Do not get in!
-괜찮아!
-맞아맞아!
-It's perfectly fine!
-Yeah, yeah!
알겠어! 저건 박사님이 만든 침입자 격퇴 장치야.
I got it! That's a trespasser repulsion machine made by the professor!
그런 건 진작에 말해 줬어야지!
You should've told that earlier!
그럼 데스펙터하고 트라이혼도 설마...
Then Despector and Trihorn could be...
어서 밖으로 나와라!
Hurry up and get out!
그러고 싶어!
We would if we could!
간다!
We're going!
트라이혼의 탐지 능력으로 재조사한 이번에야말로 수원을 찾을 수 있을 거야.
Trihorn's detection abilities will lead us to a water source this time.
야, 여기 애초에 삽질했던 곳이잖아!
Hey, we dug this place at the beginning!
뭐? 역시 수원이 있다고?
What? So there really is a water source here!
좋아. 그럼 이걸 전력으로 어떻게 할 수밖에 없구나.
Then we'll have to deal with this with full power.
스펙터 슬래시!
Spector Slash!
쳇, 힘 꽉 넣어 가자!
Tch! Let's try again with more force!
사라는 위험하니까 비켜!
You should get away from here! It's dangerous!
응!
Got it!
스펙터 슬래시!
Spector Slash!
슬래시!
Slash!
마지막 한방이다!
The last blow!
스펙터 슬래시!
Spector Slash!
됐다!
We did it!
됐다됐다!
It worked! Great!
수고했다.
Good job.
하워드 씨!
Mr. Howard!
고맙네. 날 위해서 땀 흘려가며 수원을 찾아 파 주다니.
Thank you, for finding a water source and digging a well for me.
-뭐라고?!
-웃기지 마!
-What did you say?
-Don't fool around!
이야, 역시 네가 말한 대로 우리 우물도 말라서 말야.
Just like you said, our well has dried up.
돈이라면 얼마라도 줄 테니까. 기쁘지?
I'll give money as much as you want. Happy?
웃기지 마!
Don't be stupid!
어라? 돈은 싫어? 그럼 힘으로 가져갈 텐데도?
What? You don't like money? Even if we'll take it by force if you don't?
말이 통하는 놈이 아니야!
You can't be reasonable with him!
샌드 데빌 브라더즈! 합체!
Sand Devil Brothers! Combine!
트라이혼! 넌 사라를 지켜라!
Trihorn! Protect Sarah!
샌드 데빌, 워터 건!
Sand Devil, Water Gun!
스펙터 슬래시!
Spector Slash!
뭐야?!
What?!
헤, 샌드 데빌의 장갑을 쉽게 보지 마라.
Heh, don't treat Sand Devil's exoskeleton so easily.
샌드 데빌, 테일 어택!
Sand Devil, Tail Attack!
데스펙터!
Despector!
소용 없다!
Not gonna work!
트라이혼!
Trihorn!
끝장이다!
Time to finish!
뭐, 뭐야?!
W- what?!
아키라! 류구!
Akira! Ryugu!
데스펙터! 트라이혼!
Despector! Trihorn!
그렇군! 동료를 불렀군!
I see! You've called your friends!
저 놈들도 해치워라!
Get rid of them too!
아키라! 설명은 나중에 할 테니 놈들을 지옥에 보내라!
Akira! I'll explain about this later, so throw them into hell!
뭔진 모르겠지만 알겠어!
I don't know what's going on, but got it!
류구! 건더! 헤드합체!
Ryugu! Gunder! Head Fusion!
폭투왕 다이간다!
Wild Fight King Daigunder!
헤! 어차피 겉만 번지르르할 놈들! 샌드 데빌, 워터 건!
You're mere show! Sand Devil, Water Gun!
다이간다! 드래곤 소드야!
Daigunder! Use Dragon Sword!
드래곤 소드!
Dragon Sword!
샌드 데빌! 개미지옥이다!
Sand Devil! Make an Antlion Trap!
어, 어디야?!
W- where are they?
지금이다! 데빌 캐논!
Now! Devil Cannon!
다이간다! 구멍에서 나와!
Daigunder! Get out from the hole!
지금이야, 아키라!
Now, Akira!
클러스터 파워 전개!
Activate Cluster Power!
드래곤 캐논!
Dragon Cannon!
공격!
Attack!
덤으로 슬래시!
Slash, in addition!
더 할래?
You wanna more?
만약 또 사라한테 참견하면 이번에야말로 지옥에 보내 주겠다!
If you interfere with Sarah ever again, then you're really going to hell that time!
죄송합니다!
We're sorry!
우리 승리야!
It's our victory!
다이셔틀!
Daishuttle!
정말, 박사님도 제대로 된 발명 안 한다니까.
Really, that professor never invents something proper.
너희 일이니까 걱정은 안 했다.
I didn't worry about you, since I know how you are.
보스.
Boss.
싫어, 싫어, 싫어!
No, no, no!
린, 버릇없는 소리 마!
Rin, don't be selfish!
트라이혼, 쭉 같이 있어 주겠다고 약속했잖아!
Trihorn, you promised me to be with us forever!
집에서 같이 있으면 좋잖아! 안 그래?
You can stay at my home happily! Isn't it?
뭐?!
What?!
데스펙터, 트라이혼이 뭐래?
Despector, what did Trihorn say?
만약 용서해 주겠다면 여기 남아있고 싶다고.
He's saying that he'd like to stay here if you forgive him.
트라이혼, 너!
Trihorn... you...
잠깐만.
Wait.
고마워, 트라이혼.
Thank you, Trihorn.
방금 트라이혼이 뭐라고 했는지 나도 이해했어.
I just understood what did Trihorn say.
다시 언젠간 보러 오겠다고. 그렇게 말했지?
He said that he'll come back to see us. Right?
린도 그렇게 들렸지?
Rin, did you hear that too?
응.
Yeah.
대단해, 린.
Great, Rin.
사라.
Sarah...
고마워, 트라이혼, 데스펙터. 둘 다 절대 잊지 않을 거야.
Thank you, Trihorn and Despector. We'll never forget about you guys.
약속이야! 꼭 다시 와!
It's a promise! Come see us again!
물론!
Of course!
어이!
Hey!
아빠! 엄마!
Dad! Mom!
안녕!
Bye-bye!
사실은 데스펙터도 남아있고 싶은 거 아니였어?
Despector, you wanted to stay there too, right?
어?
What?
흥, 지루하겠지! 네 그 아니꼬운 얼굴을 못 보게 된다니.
Hmph, it'll be boring, if I can't see your annoying face again!
그래, 그래! 내 아니꼬운 얼굴.
Yeah, yeah! My annoying face.
어? 데스펙터! 트라이혼!
Huh? Despector! Trihorn!
끝없는 꿈을 꾸고 있어
Dreaming an endless dream
Я сон бесконечный вижу опять перед собой
몇번이고 쓰러져도
I fall down over and over again
Как упал, и лечу вниз вновь и вновь.
저 구름 위에는 분명히
Up over those clouds
Там, где-то в высотах, за чертой облаков
푸른 하늘이 펼쳐져 있을 거야
a blue sky awaits
голубое небо ждёт меня!
강해지기 위해서라면 누구도 혼자서는
To be strong, nobody can ever become
Сильным быть, чтоб никто превзойти не смог
강해지고 뜨거워질 수 없어
strong and hot, by oneself
Стать сильней, горячей, сам я хочу!
불꽃의 Fight Fight Fighting soul
Flaming fightin' fightin' fighting soul
Так гори, душа, душа бойца!
용기를 마주치는 그 때
When you face your courage
Смелость повстречай, и пусть ведёт она тебя в жизни.
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
느껴져 바로 너라는 게
I can feel it, yes, it's you
Я это чувствую, да, это ты!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
둘은 서로의 영웅
The two are heroes of each other
Два героя - части одного, нерушимы связи,
질 수 없는 같은 내일을
They run towards to the same tomorrow
Вместе в новый день по одной тропе спешат
바라보고 달려
that they cannot lose
И не собьются с неё!
전설의 암흑수 드라고버스트가 어디 있는지 듣기 위해
To find out that Legendary Dark Beast Dragoburst is,
타이거마루하고 로우가마루가 하지메 할아버지를 채어갔어!
Tigermaru and Rougamaru took my grandpa Hajime!
큰일이야! 할아버지를 구해야 해!
That's bad! I must rescue my grandpa!
근데 내 앞에 결국 빅뱅이 나타났어!
But Big Bang showed himself in front of me at last!
빅뱅! 넌 대체 누구야!
Big Bang! Who the heck are you?
폭투선언 다이간다의 다음 이야기!
발각선언! 빅뱅의 정체!!
Next time on Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
Revelation Declaration! The True Identity of Big Bang!!